<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<resources>
	<string name="app_name">Visit Slovenia HD</string>
	<string name="toast_tts_inicializado">Text-To-Speech engine has been initialized</string>
	<string name="toast_tts_error">Error occurred while initializing Text-To-Speech engine</string>
	<string name="toast_redir">Redirecting to Google Play to install Text to Speech engine</string>
	<string name="toast_set_language">Setting TTS language to Slovenian</string>
	<string name="hola">zdravo -- Hello</string>
	<string name="di_hola">zdravo</string>
	<string name="adios">Zbogom -- Goodbye</string>
	<string name="di_adios">Zbogom</string>
	<string name="buenosdias">Dobro jutro -- Good Morning</string>
	<string name="di_buenosdias">Dobro jutro</string>
	<string name="buenas_tardes">Dober večer -- Good Evening</string>
	<string name="di_buenas_tardes">Dober večer</string>
	<string name="buenas_noches">Lahko noč -- Good Night</string>
	<string name="di_buenas_noches">Lahko noč</string>
	<string name="hasta_luego">Se vidimo kasneje -- See you later</string>
	<string name="di_hasta_luego">Se vidimo kasneje</string>
	<string name="hasta_manana">Se vidiva jutri -- See you tomorrow</string>
	<string name="di_hasta_manana">Se vidiva jutri</string>
	<string name="quetal">Kako ste? -- How are you?</string>
	<string name="di_quetal">Kako ste?</string>
	<string name="bien_gracias">počutim se dobro -- I\n m feeling good</string>
	<string name="di_bien_gracias">počutim se dobro</string>
	<string name="buen_provecho">dober tek -- Bon Appetite</string>
	<string name="di_buen_provecho">dober tek</string>
	<string name="me_puede_ayudar">Mi lahko pomagaš? -- Can you help me?</string>
	<string name="di_me_puede_ayudar">Mi lahko pomagaš?</string>
	<string name="cuanto_cuesta">Koliko je to? -- How much is it?</string>
	<string name="di_cuanto_cuesta">Koliko je to?</string>
	<string name="no_hablo_espanol">Ne govorim Sloveninan -- I don\n t speak Sloveninan</string>
	<string name="di_no_hablo_espanol">Ne govorim Sloveninan</string>
	<string name="necesito_un_medico">rabim zdravnika -- I need a doctor</string>
	<string name="di_necesito_un_medico">rabim zdravnika</string>
	<string name="soy_de_eeuu">Nisem iz Slovenije -- I´m not from Slovenia</string>
	<string name="di_soy_de_eeuu">Nisem iz Slovenije</string>
	<string name="de_donde_eres">Kje si? -- Where are you from?</string>
	<string name="di_de_donde_eres">Kje si?</string>
	<string name="me_llamo_paul">Moje ime je Peter -- My name is Peter</string>
	<string name="di_me_llamo_paul">Moje ime je Peter</string>
	<string name="como_se_llama">Kaj ti je ime? -- What is your name?</string>
	<string name="di_como_se_llama">Kaj ti je ime?</string>
	<string name="arriba">navzgor -- up</string>
	<string name="di_arriba">navzgor</string>
	<string name="abajo">navzdol -- Down</string>
	<string name="di_abajo">navzdol</string>
	<string name="izquierda">Levi -- Left</string>
	<string name="di_izquierda">Levi</string>
	<string name="derecha">Prav -- Right</string>
	<string name="di_derecha">Prav</string>
	<string name="centro">Bližnji -- Middle</string>
	<string name="di_centro">Bližnji</string>
	<string name="delante">spredaj -- Front</string>
	<string name="di_delante">spredaj</string>
	<string name="detras">Nazaj -- Back</string>
	<string name="di_detras">Nazaj</string>
	<string name="encima">Več kot -- Over</string>
	<string name="di_encima">Več kot</string>
	<string name="debajo">Spodaj -- Under</string>
	<string name="di_debajo">Spodaj</string>
	<string name="lo_siento">Žal -- Sorry</string>
	<string name="di_lo_siento">Žal</string>
	<string name="por_favor">Prosimo -- Please</string>
	<string name="di_por_favor">Prosimo</string>
	<string name="gracias">Hvala vam -- Thank you</string>
	<string name="di_gracias">Hvala vam</string>
	<string name="de_nada">Ni za kaj -- You are welcome</string>
	<string name="di_de_nada">Ni za kaj</string>
	<string name="muchas_gracias">Najlepša hvala -- Thank you very much</string>
	<string name="di_muchas_gracias">Najlepša hvala</string>
	<string name="no_gracias">Ne, hvala -- No, thank you</string>
	<string name="di_no_gracias">Ne, hvala</string>
	<string name="encantado">Lepo te je bilo srečati -- Nice to meet you</string>
	<string name="di_encantado">Lepo te je bilo srečati</string>
	<string name="esta_bien">To je v redu -- That is OK</string>
	<string name="di_esta_bien">To je v redu</string>
	<string name="un_cafe">Ena kava, prosim -- One coffee, please</string>
	<string name="di_un_cafe">Ena kava, prosim</string>
	<string name="una_cerveza">Eno pivo prosim -- One beer, please</string>
	<string name="di_una_cerveza">Eno pivo prosim</string>
	<string name="el_bano">Kje je stranišče? -- Where is the toilette?</string>
	<string name="di_el_bano">Kje je stranišče?</string>
	<string name="la_carta">Ali mi lahko poveste meni, prosim? -- Could you give me the menu, please?</string>
	<string name="di_la_carta">Ali mi lahko poveste meni, prosim?</string>
	<string name="una_tortilla">Ena omleta, prosim -- One omelette, please</string>
	<string name="di_una_tortilla">Ena omleta, prosim</string>
	<string name="una_paella">Nekateri Golaz prosim -- Some Golaž please</string>
	<string name="di_una_paella">Nekateri Golaz prosim</string>
	<string name="la_cuenta">Ali mi lahko prinese račun, prosim? -- Could you bring me the bill, please?</string>
	<string name="di_la_cuenta">Ali mi lahko prinese račun, prosim?</string>
	<string name="desayuno">zajtrk -- Breakfast</string>
	<string name="di_desayuno">zajtrk</string>
	<string name="comida">Kosilo -- Lunch</string>
	<string name="di_comida">Kosilo</string>
	<string name="cena">večerja -- Dinner</string>
	<string name="di_cena">večerja</string>
	<string name="cuchara">Spoon -- Spoon</string>
	<string name="di_cuchara">Spoon</string>
	<string name="tenedor">vilice -- Fork</string>
	<string name="di_tenedor">vilice</string>
	<string name="cuchillo">nož -- Knife</string>
	<string name="di_cuchillo">nož</string>
	<string name="pan">kruh -- Bread</string>
	<string name="di_pan">kruh</string>
	<string name="vaso">steklo -- Glass</string>
	<string name="di_vaso">steklo</string>
	<string name="agua">voda -- Water</string>
	<string name="di_agua">voda</string>
	<string name="servilleta">prtiček -- Napkin</string>
	<string name="di_servilleta">prtiček</string>
	<string name="camarero">Natakar -- Waiter</string>
	<string name="di_camarero">Natakar</string>
	<string name="me_gusta">všeč mi je -- I like it</string>
	<string name="di_me_gusta">všeč mi je</string>
	<string name="si">Da -- Yes</string>
	<string name="di_si">Da</string>
	<string name="no">Ne -- No</string>
	<string name="di_no">Ne</string>
	<string name="es_posible">Lahko bi bilo -- It could be</string>
	<string name="di_es_posible">Lahko bi bilo</string>
	<string name="nunca">Nikoli -- Never</string>
	<string name="di_nunca">Nikoli</string>
	<string name="siempre">Nenehno -- Always</string>
	<string name="di_siempre">Nenehno</string>
	<string name="a_veces">včasih -- Sometimes</string>
	<string name="di_a_veces">včasih</string>
	<string name="hoy">danes -- Today</string>
	<string name="di_hoy">danes</string>
	<string name="ayer">včeraj -- Yesterday</string>
	<string name="di_ayer">včeraj</string>
	<string name="manana">jutri -- Tomorrow</string>
	<string name="di_manana">jutri</string>
	<string name="coche">avto -- Car</string>
	<string name="di_coche">avto</string>
	<string name="avion">plane -- Plane</string>
	<string name="di_avion">plane</string>
	<string name="tren">vlak -- Train</string>
	<string name="di_tren">vlak</string>
	<string name="autobus">Avtobus -- Bus</string>
	<string name="di_autobus">Avtobus</string>
	<string name="bicicleta">koles -- Bicycle</string>
	<string name="di_bicicleta">koles</string>
	<string name="hotel">Hotel -- Hotel</string>
	<string name="di_hotel">Hotel</string>
	<string name="habitacion">soba -- Room</string>
	<string name="di_habitacion">soba</string>
	<string name="habitacion_reservada">Sem bil nagrajen z eno sobo -- I have booked one room</string>
	<string name="di_habitacion_reservada">Sem bil nagrajen z eno sobo</string>
	<string name="hasta_pronto">Se vidiva kmalu! -- See you soon!</string>
	<string name="di_hasta_pronto">Se vidiva kmalu!</string>
	<string name="Salir">Exit</string>
	<string name="basic_data">Basic data</string>
	<string name="basic_data_text">"Basic data \n  Land area \n  20,273 sq km, of which 66% wooded areas, 28% agricultural areas and 3% built‑up areas \n \n Population \n 2.06m (January 1st 2015; Republic of Slovenia Statistics Office) \n main urban centres \n Population in ’000 (January 1st 2015; Republic of Slovenia Statistics Office) \n Ljubljana (capital): 287.2 \n Maribor: 112.3 \n Kranj: 55.9 \n Celje: 48.8 \n Climate \n Mediterranean on the coast, continental inland \n Weather in Ljubljana (altitude 295 metres) \n Hottest month: July, 21°C; coldest month: January, -1°C (average daily maximum and minimum); driest months: January and February, 75 mm average rainfall; wettest month: June, 183 mm average rainfall \n Language \n Slovene \n Weights and measures \n Metric system \n Currency \n The euro (€), which replaced the Slovenian tolar (SIT) on January 1st 2007 at a fixed exchange rate of SIT239.64:€1 \n Time \n One hour ahead of GMT; two hours ahead in summer \n Fiscal year \n Calendar year \n Public holidays \n January 1st (New Year\n s Day), February 8th (Preseren Day), April 16th-17th (Easter Day and Easter Monday), April 27th (Uprising Against the Occupation Day), May 1st-2nd (Labour Day), June 25th (National Day), August 15th (Assumption of Mary), October 31st (Reformation Day), November 1st (Remembrance Day), December 25th (Christmas Day), December 26th (Independence and National Unity Day \n "</string>
	<string name="arrival">How to arrive</string>
	<string name="arrival_text">"Easy Access \n Slovenia is situated in Central Europe and borders Italy, Austria, Hungary and Croatia. It is only a few hour drive away from Venice or Vienna. Slovenia is easily accessible from all neighbouring countries, as it has good road and rail connections, with daily flights from many European cities. Since it is a coastal country, you can also get to Slovenia by sea.\n \n By Car\n Most of the cars enter Slovenia by motorways, which is also the easiest way to travel around the country. It is easy to travel the Slovenian roads by car, since they are well and clearly signposted. Although some local roads are narrow and winding, a drive along them is nevertheless pleasant and varied. For driving on motorways, it is mandatory for you to have a vignette.\n \n By Air\n In addition to the daily flights to many European cities, there are two low-cost flight providers flying from the main Slovenian international airport Jože Pučnik Ljubljana. They are EasyJet and Wizz Air, flying to London and Brussels. Most flights to Ljubljana are made by the only Slovenian airline Adria Airways. You can also fly to one of the foreign airports in the near vicinity, and access Slovenia from there by bus, train or rental car.\n \n By Bus\n Buses run to Slovenia from many European cities. In Slovenia, you can also get to most of the towns and the countryside by bus. If they run along local roads, the drivers can stop at a bus stop in any settlement. You can buy a bus ticket directly from the bus driver, while at major bus stops you can also buy a bus ticket for a specific date.\n \n By Train\n Trains to Slovenia run daily from many European cities. If travelling by train, it is also possible to ride in a sleeping car. There are only the trains of Slovenian Railways running around Slovenia, with all the timetables and price lists published on the web pages. You can buy a ticket at every railway station as well as on the train. Slovenian trains stick to the timetables.\n \n By Boat or Sailboat\n From May to October, there are frequent rides of high-speed power boats from Venice, Trieste, Poreč and Rovinj. Occasionally, large cruise ships arrive to Koper. If you arrive with your own vessel, you should know that the international border crossings are only in Koper and Piran, and from May to October in Izola as well. In Izola, Koper and Portorož, there are modern marinas available for mooring. In several places on the Slovenian coast, you can rent a sailboat.\n \n By Bicycle\n Naturally, you can also get to Slovenia by bicycle, whether by riding the roads or by taking a train. By bicycle, you can drive on all roads in Slovenia. The only exceptions are the expressways and motorways. It is also prohibited to ride your bicycle along the forest and mountain trails.\n "</string>
	<string name="climate">Climate</string>
	<string name="climate_text">"Climate\n The climate of the Slovenia can be described as typical European continental influenced climate with warm, dry summers and fairly cold winters, while the coastal areas and the lowlands in the south have a mediterranean influenced climate. January is the coldest month with daytime temperatures usually around zero in the north, but in some cases winter months can be very cold with temperatures far below zero and strong, cold northeasterly winds, called Bora, especially in the mountainous regions, where the weather is strongly influenced by the nearby Alps. Heavy snowfall or even snowstorms are also possible on some days there; the yearly average number of days with snow is less than 40 in the low-land regions and up to 120 days in the mountainous regions of Slovenia. In the coastal areas long-lasting frost periods and snow are quite seldom because of the influence of the warm water temperatures of the mediterranean sea.\n \n In summer daytime temperatures reach 20-25°C, but sometimes quite higher, 30°C or more. In most of the time is dry weather with sunny spells, although sometimes heavy Thunderstorms can occur at the end of the day, especially in the mountainous regions. July is the warmest month with an average Temperature of 22°C. Annual Precipitation varies from 400 mm in the southern lowland areas, and up to 1000 mm in the mountainous regions.\n \n The weather is best May-September, when days are warm and the nights are cool, although it rains more in spring than in summer. Autumn and winter are usually a little chilly and wet, and often foggy in the mountainous regions.\n \n Required clothing:\n Lightweight cottons and linens during summer months; warmer medium-weights to heavyweights and rainwear during the winter. A sweater may be needed in the evenings or for trekking in the mountains, even in the summer.\n \n Koeppen-Geiger classification:\n The Climate of Slowenia can be classified as Cfb Climate; a warm temperated humid climate with the warmest month lower than 22°C over average and four or more months above 10°C over average.The climate of some coastal areas of Slovenia can be classified as Cfa Climate; a warm temperated mediterranean climate with the warmest month above 22°C over average and humid conditions all year round.\n "</string>
	<string name="attractions">Turistic Attractions</string>
	<string name="attractions_text">"There are many turistic attractions that are nice to be seen in Slovenia like the Lake Bled, Postojna Caves, Triglav National Park, Isonzo the Motorrail, Piran, Velika Planina, Logar and many others \n \n  You can enjoy Slovenia in any month of the year and you can make many kinds of tourism in such a small country.There are activities like cycling, trekking, climbing, active holidays, spas and resorts, caves, nature, food and wine, culture, shopping, family fun, casinos, and so on \n \n  Check the following buttons." </string>
	<string name="bled">Lake Bled</string>
	<string name="bled_text">"Lake Bled\n  (Slovene: Blejsko jezero; German: Bleder See, Veldeser See) is a lake in the Julian Alps of the Upper Carniolan region of northwestern Slovenia, where it adjoins the town of Bled. \n The area is a tourist destination. The lake is 35 km (22 mi) from Ljubljana International Airport and 55 km (34 mi) from the capital city, Ljubljana."</string>
	<string name="postoina">Postoina Caves</string>
	<string name="postoina_text">"Postojna Cave \n  (Slovene: Postojnska jama; German: Adelsberger Grotte; Italian: Grotte di Postumia) is a 24,340 m long karst cave system near Postojna, southwestern Slovenia. \n It is the second-longest cave system in the country (following the Migovec System)[ as well as one of its top tourism sites. The caves were created by the Pivka River."</string>
	<string name="triglav">Triglav</string>
	<string name="triglav_text">"Triglav National Park (TNP) \n (Slovene: Triglavski narodni park) is the only national park in Slovenia. It was established in its modern form in 1981 and is located in the northwestern part of the country, respectively the southeastern part of the Alpine massif. \n Mount Triglav, the highest peak of Julian Alps, stands almost in the middle of the national park. From it the valleys spread out radially, supplying water to two large river systems with their sources in the Julian Alps: the Soča and the Sava, flowing to the Adriatic and Black Sea, respectively"</string>
	<string name="isonzo">Isonzo</string>
	<string name="isonzo_text">"The Soča (pronounced [ˈsoːtʃa] in Slovene) or Isonzo (pronounced [iˈzontso] in Italian) (other names Friulian: Lusinç, German: Sontig, Latin: Aesontius or Isontius) is a 138-kilometre (86 mi) long river that flows through western Slovenia (96 kilometres or 60 miles) and northeastern Italy (43 kilometres or 27 miles).\n An Alpine river in character, its source lies in the Trenta Valley in the Julian Alps in northwestern Slovenia, at an elevation of 876 metres (2,874 ft).[3] The river runs past the towns of Bovec, Kobarid, Tolmin, Kanal ob Soči, Nova Gorica (where it is crossed by the Solkan Bridge), and Gorizia, entering the Adriatic Sea close to the town of Monfalcone. It has a nival-pluvial regime in its upper course and pluvial-nival in its lower course.\n Prior to the First World War, the river formed part of the border between Kingdom of Italy and the Austro-Hungarian Empire.[citation needed] During World War I, it was the scene of bitter fighting between the two countries, culminating in the Battle of Caporetto in 1917"</string>
	<string name="motorail">Motorail</string>
	<string name="motorail_text">"Motorail trains operate on the line between Bohinjska Bistrica, Podbrdo and Most na Soči, and run through the longest Slovenian rail tunnel\n  \n Ever wanted to go on a longer journey by car without having to drive the distance? Then try the motorail service, which carries your car while you relax and enjoy the train ride. \n  Motorail trains operate on the line between Bohinjska Bistrica, Podbrdo and Most na Soči, and run through the longest Slovenian rail tunnel, the Bohinj tunnel, connecting Upper Carniola in the North of Slovenia with the seaside Littoral in the South West. Motorail trains can carry cars, vans, pickups, and camper vans which don\n t exceed 3m in height and 2.4m in width. "</string>
	<string name="piran">Piran</string>
	<string name="piran_text">The most beautiful town on the Slovenian coast grew with the help of salt. The Piran salt pans, where the world-class fleur de sel (flower of salt) is still produced today using age-old methods, were the reason why the picturesque Mediterranean walled town, with its church with a view and cultural attractions, flourished. \n  \n  The old port town with remnants of a medieval wall is protected as a cultural and historical monument. Narrow streets with closely constructed houses descending from the hill and its church to the central square on the coast only emphasise its Mediterranean character. This worldly coastal town, which developed under the influence of Venice, is considered to be one of the most authentic and most photogenic towns on the Adriatic coast. In addition to architecture, the Maritime Museum, an aquarium and other attractions, visitors flock to this town to enjoy events, the culinary offerings, and nearby special natural features. \n  \n  Piran is one of the picturesque medieval towns of Slovenia. Lovers of defensive walls and other architectural and cultural features from times gone by can travel in Slovenia for a week, going from one historical town to another, from the coast to Ljubljana, and from the Alps to the Pannonian Plain. \n  \n  The Piran Salt Pans, established in 804, encompassed the salt pans in the area of today’s marina (Lucija, Portorož), the smaller Strunjan Salt Pans, and the larger Sečovlje Salt Pans. The areas of all the preserved salt pans are now landscape parks. At the Strunjan Landscape Park, you will find an incredible cliff towering over the sea, and at the Sečovlje Salt Pans, you can learn about the traditional salt production with guided tours and a visit to the Museum of Salt-Making. \n  \n  Every August, Piran, a town that grew on salt, celebrates the Saltern Festival that revives the return of the saltern families from the Sečovlje saltpans, where they would spend their summers until the final salt harvest. The main events take place in Tartini Square, which is dedicated to the grand violin virtuoso and composer Giuseppe Tartini, born in Piran. Every summer, the Tartini Festival of chamber music takes place in the town. The town, where painters return time and again to gain inspiration, also offers a number of other events. Follow the calendar of events in Piran!</string>
	<string name="velika">Velika Planina</string>
	<string name="velika_text">The end of spring is when the cowbells out on the Alpine pastures of the Velika Planina plateau start ringing, announcing the arrival of herdsmen. It’s a magical plateau with one of the largest herdsmen’s settlements in Europe. And you’re invited to learn about the fascinating life on the mountain pasture and sample the dairy goodies they’ll prepare for you. Go for a walk through the meadows or take a hike (or mountain bike) across the plateau. \n  \n  Velika Planina invites with plenty of opportunities for walks and hikes across the mountain pasture showcasing natural and ethnological curiosities that you won’t want to miss. The fastest way to Velika Planina is by cable car from Kamniška Bistrica. From there, you can take a ski lift to the top, where you’ll be greeted with a magnificent view. Those who prefer a challenge can follow one of the well-marked footpaths to the top. In the winter, there’s a ski slope that will conjure up a true winter fairy tale for you to remember, together with friends and family. \n  \n  The herdsmen’s settlement on the pasture comprises some 140 huts. With its characteristic architecture, it’s the symbol of Velika Planina. The huts are covered with roofs made of traditional spruce shingles that reach almost down to the ground. The plateau really comes alive in June, with the arrival of shepherds who occupy the huts until September as they tend to their grazing herds. They’re only too happy to invite visitors for a taste of their homemade dairy delicacies, or even prepare an authentic shepherd’s lunch – sour milk and žganci – buckwheat or corn mush. Some of the huts are available to visitors, so there’s no reason why you couldn’t spend a night or two like the shepherds do. \n  \n  Take a break at the chapel of Snow Mary and descend to the famous Vetrnica cave, which is accessible via a narrow circular footpath. On the western edge of the plateau (Zeleni Rob) there\n s a picturesque natural window called Luknja (hole). The Dovja Griča cave (meaning wild rock) is located in the Tiha Dolina valley (Slovene for quiet valley), which is only nine metres deep, but known for the many folk tales that it inspired. Another site worth seeing is Preskar Museum where trnič is kept – a special kind of cheese characteristic of the Velika Planina area. \n  \n  In the summer you can pick yourself up on the plateau with an authentic shepherd’s lunch – sour milk and žganci (buckwheat mush). The shepherds will be happy to offer you homemade cheese and other dairy specialties when you visit. Once on the plateau you can recharge your batteries with traditional shepherd\n s food, such as jota (bean and sauerkraut hotpot), ričet (barley stew), goulash, sausage with sauerkraut, Carniola sausage, buckwheat žganci or rolled dumplings with cottage cheese known as štruklji. \n  \n  Under Velika Planina, in the midst of pristine nature, you’ll discover three springs of the Kamniška Bistrica river. The best known of them is its main source, located near the mountain lodge Dom v Kamniški Bistrici. At the source you’ll find Plečnik Manor, a lodge designed by the famous Slovenian architect so as to blend naturally with the landscape. While tracing the river don’t forget to visit two gorges: Veliki and Mali Predaselj, the narrowest part of the Kamniška Bistrica riverbed, and the Orglice (Slovene for harmonica) waterfall is also well worth seeing.</string>
	<string name="logar">Logar</string>
	<string name="logar_text">The Logar Valley (Logarska dolina) is one of the most beautiful Alpine glacial valleys in Europe. The harmonic balance between tradition, man and nature that found its home in this part of the Solčava Region is both exceptional and difficult to find. Make your stay in this peaceful landscape park an opportunity for hiking, cycling, horseback riding or a photo safari. The park has also won the international CIPRA Future in the Alps Award for successful management of the protected area. \n  \n  In the Logar Valley you can admire pristine green nature at every step. Take the Trail through the Logar Valley, a natural historic and ethnographic trail leading through the fascinating nooks and crannies amidst the unspoilt nature of the landscape park. You’ll have the opportunity to discover extraordinary, rare and even endangered flower species. The valley is known also for its many waterfalls, the most notable among which is the 90-metre Rinka Falls. \n  \n  If it’s active holidays you’re after you can set off for the nearby peaks, go cycling, climb a mountain or go photo hunting for animals in their natural environment. Children enjoy roaming the fairy tale forest that hides many of their favourite fairy tale characters. Come winter the valley is especially inviting for cross-country skiing, sledding, downhill skiing and ski touring; and if you’re up to it, you’re sure to enjoy climbing the frozen waterfalls. \n  \n  Wooden granaries or ‘kašče’ are an integral part of the cultural heritage – not only in the Logar Valley, but also in the Solčava region and the Upper Savinja Valley. They were an indispensable part of agricultural holdings, as they were used for storing foodstuffs, especially grains. Some of them are still used for their original purpose. Also see the Home of Spiritual Retreat, the Logarski Kot Herdsman’s Hut and the Chapel of Christ the King. \n  \n  The Logar Valley is one of three valleys in the Solčava Region – the other two to be discovered are Robanov Kot and Matkov Kot. Most of Solčava Region’s residents live on high-mountain farms, among which is the highest-lying farm in Slovenia (Bukovnik, 1,327 m). Climb uphill to the mountain huts and peaks or soar above the Logar Valley in a glider. Make this beautiful environment the setting for your new adventures.</string>
	<string name="vine">World’s Oldest Vine</string>
	<string name="vine_text">The heart of Maribor, Lent, is home to the oldest vine in the world. At more than 450 years old it’s the only plant boasting its own museum – the Old Vine House. Maribor hosts a number of events celebrating the Old Vine, such as the Pruning of the Old Vine, St. Martin’s Day, and the Old Vine Festival. Believe it or not, the Old Vine even has its own anthem, and the locals are only too keen to let you hear it. \n  \n  Žametovka or modra kavčina (Bleu de Cologne), confirmed at 400 years of age, is listed in the Guinness Book of Records as the oldest vine in the world still producing fruit. The old vine was planted in Maribor at the end of the Middle Ages during the Turkish invasions. It witnessed – and survived – the battles that raged between the invaders and defenders of the city, for the Old Vine House of today was once part of the city wall. \n  \n  Set out on gastronomic journeys through the city of Maribor and its surroundings. You can enjoy a vast variety of Štajerska flavours, and all paths will lead you to the Old Vine House.\n  \n  The Old Vine is the only plant with its own museum – the Old Vine House. Once part of the city wall, the house today showcases a venerable wine heritage, with a winery and a wine tasting room offering premium wines from the Maribor wine region. And to celebrate the Old Vine, Maribor and vicinity boast numerous picturesque wine roads and wineries. \n  \n  With an array of culinary, wine and cultural delicacies this premium festival event begins in October with the ceremonial grape harvest of the Old Vine and closes with the Feast of St. Martin in Maribor, the biggest St. Martin’s Day celebration in Slovenia. You’ll be able to experience the best that Slovenian wine producers, especially those from the Štajerska region, have to offer. Fans of traditional culinary delights will be able to sample authentic dishes by local chefs, and there’s also an exciting cultural programme to round it all off. \n  \n  The second-largest Slovenian city Maribor prides itself with the oldest vine in the world, which is more than 400 years old. There are three wine routes from this venerable wine “lady” to the countryside of Maribor and you can ride your bicycle on them. Individual points of the three wine routes are connected with the international Archduke Johann Trail from Graz to Maribor. If you are not one of the most enthusiastic cyclists, you can also ride an electric bicycle and ride along these roads.</string>
	<string name="regions">Regions</string>
	<string name="regions_text">In Slovenia, one can experience four different worlds in a single day, since even the remotest corners of the country are only about two hours away from the capital city of Ljubljana. In the green heart of Slovenia your view stretches from the mountainous Alps to the tranquil beauty of the Pannonian plain in the east. Mediterranean Slovenia, with its coastal towns and the stunning Karst, is waiting for you to discover it in all its beauty. Feel the vibrant pulse of the capital city, explore the beauty of nature and culture in the surrounding area. \n  \n  You can feel the beauty of green Slovenia as you enjoy a view of the famous Lake Bled and the beloved Lake Bohinj. There are countless opportunities for outdoor activities amidst the picturesque Alpine peaks and valleys embraced by the Julian Alps, Triglav National Park, the mighty Kamnik and Savinja Alps, and the green Pohorje Mountains. Either head to Maribor, the city with the oldest grapevine in the world, the renowned holiday destination of Kranjska Gora, the stunning region of Koroška, or visit the Soča River Valley – no matter where you go, an incredible experience awaits you. \n  \n  While the Mediterranean towns of Piran, Izola and Koper entice visitors with their medieval town centres, Portorož invites them with its holiday attractions. Salt harvesters can be seen hard at work on the Sečovlje Salt Pans, and the Karst with Postojna Cave, Škocjan Caves and Vilenica cave boasts the most stunning underground worlds on the planet. This region is also home to the noble Lipizzaner horse. The land of vine-rich hills of Goriška Brda is famous for its enticing high-quality aromatic wine, and you can taste it at tourist farms and in wineries. With its myriad of exciting tastes and adventures, the Vipava Valley has also been recommended by the prestigious Lonely Planet, the travel guidebook giant. \n  \n  Eastern Slovenia is a land of wide, open fields and rolling landscapes, storks, wind-rattles, floating mills, healing waters, energy points, picturesque rolling vineyards, unique traditions and dialects, and, most importantly, it’s home to warm and hospitable people. This landscape is rich in natural thermal spas that will strengthen and re-energise you. Discover the friendliness and hospitality of tourism farms, where you can taste local delicacies, and stay overnight in a charming vineyard cottage amidst vineyards. To relive the past, you can visit numerous majestic castles. \n  \n  Ljubljana and its surroundings offer their visitors countless opportunities to spend their holidays, explore, and enjoy. The green capital is known for various original ideas created by young entrepreneurs, researchers, artists, students, and the lovers of all things beautiful. For a brief break from the city, go on one of the many day-trips, as Ljubljana offers quick access to several nearby attractions. You can either enter the kingdom of the brown bear in the forests of the Kočevsko region, learn about the tradition of herdsmen or visit charming historical towns inscribed as UNESCO World Heritage Sites.</string>
	<string name="active">Active Holidays</string>
	<string name="active_text">Climb a summit. On foot or by bike. Enjoy lovely ski slopes with your children. Feel the adrenaline. Inhale freshness. In the middle of green forests, on a horse, next to water, on golf courses. Enter the world of active adventures. \n  \n  Spend your holiday in the heart of mountainous Slovenia. Walk through the dynamic and untouched nature with 10,000 kilometres of marked and arranged hiking trails. You can choose from 175 mountain huts or spend a night in hotels and camps for hikers. Go hiking and inhale the freshness of the mountains. \n  \n  The dynamic landscapes of Slovenia, with their countless natural beauties, are ideal for a biking holiday. Here, you are sure to find trails suitable for you, your friends, and your family. Due to the influence of the Mediterranean climate, you can go biking in Slovenia almost all year round. \n  \n  Slovenia is rich in natural water sources, which almost call for activities on or near the water. Refresh yourself with a swim in the sea, lakes, rivers or in swimming pools. Sail and surf on the water and let the wind curl your hair. Enjoy in stand-up paddle boarding or row the boat on the crystal-clear waters. Do you feel adrenaline rush? Experience white water rafting, kayaking or canoeing and discover the beauties of the narrow gorges. To relax, go fishing or slowly raft down the Slovenian rivers. \n  \n  Do you enjoy special experiences? When your soul rejoices and your heart pounds. Take a look at Slovenia from a different perspective. See the landscape from the air, hear the sound of rushing water, feel the adrenaline tension. This is an experience that will change your holidays into an unforgettable life event. \n  \n  The golf courses of Slovenia are among the most beautiful in Europe. They are set in typical landscapes on the edge of the Pannonian Plain, among vineyards and rolling hills, below Alpine summits, and in the idyllic karst landscape. Due to the short distances within Slovenia, you can reach most of the golf clubs from Ljubljana within one hour. \n  \n  Equestrianism and horseback riding in Slovenia have a centuries-old tradition thanks to the Lipica Stud Farm, the cradle of the world-famous Lipizzaner horses. Numerous equestrian centres, tourist farms and ranches offer you the experience of Slovenia in the saddle. \n  \n  When snowflakes dance in the sky and create a wonderful winter landscape, it is time to have some fun on the snow. In addition to well-maintained ski runs, many other winter activities await you in Slovenia. Enter the world of unforgettable adventures on snow and ice. </string>
	<string name="biking">Biking</string>
	<string name="biking_text">Explore Slovenia by bike. The dynamic landscapes of Slovenia, with their countless natural beauties, are ideal for a biking holiday. \n  \n  Here, you are sure to find trails suitable for you, your friends, and your family. Due to the influence of the Mediterranean climate, you can go biking in Slovenia almost all year round. \n  \n  Hop on a bicycle and take a ride along the trails through Slovenia’s most extensive forest, ascend the picturesque plateau in Central Slovenia and enjoy a ride through hilly landscapes. You can also explore the city streets and squares by bicycle. </string>
	<string name="bohinj">Lake Bohinj</string>
	<string name="bohinj_text">The largest natural lake in Slovenia with endless opportunities for outdoor activities. \n  \n 
Lake Bohinj is located in a glacial valley and it comprises almost 100 million cubic metres of water – according to an old Bohinj joke: no more than a bucket if it is large enough. The steeply descending lake basin is relatively smoothly shaped and has no shallow areas. In summer, the temperature of the water rises to 22 °C; in winter, the lake freezes sometimes. Water level rises 2 – 3 metres after heavy rainfall. \n  \n  Lake water is restored three times per year. The main tributary is the Savica, and the main distributary is the Sava Bohinjka. More than a third of the water flows into the lake from the Karst springs under the lake surface along the northern shore. During heavy rainfall, the Karst waters gush out as the Govic spring on the Pršivec hillside. \n  \n  Lake Bohinj is perfect for water activities all year round – from swimming, boat riding, wind surfing, kayaking or canoeing, fishing and diving in warmer months, to (sometimes) even ice skating in winter. Visitors can also take a wonderful tourist boat ride or simply go for a relaxing walk along the shore. If ice stating is an option, please be aware, that you can only skate and walk on ice at your own responsibility. We recommend you to be extremely cautious!</string>
	<string name="spa">Spa break and water fun</string>
	<string name="spa_text">Slovenian spas have an abundance of outdoor and indoor water areas for swimming in all seasons. Moreover, they also have massage and therapeutic pools, and very attractive water parks with slides. Entertainment for children is also available. \n  \n  All thermal health resorts in Slovenia have modern swimming pools with thermal water or seawater heated to various pleasant temperatures. These pools have areas for hydro massage, whirlpools, and other relaxing elements. Some health resorts even have Olympic-size pools. \n  \n  Spas with large outdoor water parks with fast water chutes, slow rivers, surfing areas, and daring slides appeal to those who love water adventures. Among them is the first water slide with a 360-degree loop. \n  \n  If you go to the pool, you can enjoy group exercise with an instructor, which will provide you with moments of fun and take care of your health. Various kinds of water aerobics and other forms of exercise improve your circulation, allow you to exhale better, and strengthen your respiratory muscles. And they’re fun. \n  \n  In addition to pools, Slovenian spas also provide many outdoor sunbathing, food and beverage areas. Some spas even have sunbathing terraces for nudists. In summer in particular, there are numerous themed adventures for children. \n  \n  Most Slovenian spas have kiddie pools for toddlers and lovely pools for children. Children-friendly entertainment is full of adventures and stories about local and other, more well-known, heroes. Meet dwarves and elves, pirates and Indians! Massages for children and child care are also available.</string>
	<string name="Otras_apps">Other apps</string>
	<string name="Acerca">About</string>
	<string name="Rate">Rate</string>
	<string name="about">About</string>
	<string name="subject1">Have a look at this app!</string>
	<string name="textoabout">Concept by Mymma Soto \n  Developed By APlanetBit \n  Icons from Icons Land \n  http://www.icons-land.com</string>
	<string name="version">Version</string>
	<string name="extra_text1">This application is very useful! \n Try it! \n  https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=</string>
	<string name="mensaje_cookies">"According to Directive 2002/58 / EC of the European Parliament and the Council it is informed that this site device identifiers are used to personalize content and ads, in order to provide social media features and to analyze traffic . We also share these identifiers and other information on your device with our social media partners, advertising and web analytics. More details on http://lagatera.dynu.net "</string>
	<string name="map_of_slovenia">Map</string>
	<string name="vocabulario">Vocabulary</string>
	<string name="slovenia">Slovenia</string>
</resources>